Guide to the Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman Papers TAM.720
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman Papers
1974-2017
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Snitow, Alan
Kaufman, Deborah, 1955-
United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation
TAM.720
6.75 Linear Feet in 5 record cartons, 3 manuscript boxes, and 1 half manuscript box
6 sound discs (cd)
8 videodiscs (dvd)
The Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman Papers contain research materials and personal files related to the work of journalists and filmmakers Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman. Half of the collection documents Snitow and Kaufman's film company Snitow-Kaufman Productions, which includes research and promotional materials related to their films. Two boxes include FBI files used as research for the documentary Between Two Worlds. Papers related to their other documentaries feature interviews, film transcripts, and press materials for the films Blacks and Jews, Thirst, Drones in My Backyard, Between Two Worlds, Secrets of Silicon Valley, Company Town, and Offshoring. The collection also contains two boxes of Alan Snitow's files documenting his work at KPFA-Pacifica Radio, as well as diaries and interview notes from a 1989 trip to the Soviet Union.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman in March 2017. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 2017.019 and 2017.072.
Arrangement
Alan Snitow's files related to his work at Pacifica Radio are arranged in roughly chronological order. Snitow-Kaufman Production files are grouped by material type. This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Historical Note
Filmmakers Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman have made eight short and feature-length documentaries through their film company Snitow-Kaufman Productions. Their feature-length documentaries include Blacks and Jews (1997), Secrets of Silicon Valley (2001), Thirst (2004), Between Two Worlds (2011), and Company Town (2017), the majority of which have aired on Public Broadcasting Service (PBS) programs "POV" and "Independent Lens." The documentary Between Two Worlds was intended to be featured on "POV" under the title "Discontinuity," but was eventually released independently in 2011.
Deborah Kaufman was also director and founder of the San Francisco Jewish Film Festival, which she ran for 13 years.
Alan Snitow is a journalist who worked for 12 years as a producer at KTVU-TV News, the Bay Area Fox new station, and as News Director and reporter at the Bay Area's Pacifica Radio station, KPFA-FM in the 1970s and 1980s.
Scope and Contents
The Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman Papers contain research materials and personal files related to the work of journalists and filmmakers Alan Snitow and Deborah Kaufman. Half of the collection documents Snitow and Kaufman's production company Snitow-Kaufman Productions, which includes research and promotional materials related to their films. Two boxes contain FBI files used as research for the documentary Between Two Worlds. The documentary focused on communist purges within the American Jewish Congress (AJC). These materials include Alan Snitow's Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests for FBI files on the AJC, the Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, the American Jewish Committee, and individual AJC members including Billie Portnow, Judith Pollack, Stanley Levison, Shad and Justine Polier. Alan Snitow also submitted FOIA requests for files on his parents Virginia Levitt Snitow and Charles Snitow, but those files are not included in the collection.
Materials related to other documentaries in the collection include interviews, film transcripts, and press materials for documentaries produced between 1994 and 2015. Documentaries for which these materials are available include Blacks and Jews, Thirst, Drones in My Backyard, Between Two Worlds, Secrets of Silicon Valley, Company Town, and Offshoring. These documentaries touch on topics including Jewish identity, relationships between Jews and African Americans, American business, technology industries, and access to drinking water.
The collection contains two boxes of Alan Snitow's files documenting his work at KPFA-Pacifica Radio. Alan Snitow was News Director of the Pacifica Radio's Bay Area station KPFA-FM during the 1970s and 1980s. His files include proposals and drafts for news stories, fundraising work, news department training documents, and administrative files related to his work as News Director. They also document disputes between Pacifica management and staff between 1997 and 2000.
Other materials in the collection include diaries, interviews, and tape logs from a trip Snitow took to the Soviet Union in 1989. Snitow used some of his research from this trip in his reporting at KPFA, but his diaries also document his personal experiences during his travels.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Jewish communists -- United States.; Anti-communist movements -- United States.; Religion and politics.; Alternative radio broadcasting.; Documentary films -- United States.; Jews -- United States -- Identity.; African Americans -- Relations with Jews.; High technology industries -- United States.; Drone aircraft.; American Jewish Congress; American Jewish Committee
- Snitow Kaufman Productions:Between Two Worlds: Research Material, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Box 2)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Chinatown Doc and Schools, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Sunday News Collective Stories: Chile, Sahel, Drought, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Hiring, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: KPFA Strike, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Pacifica Politics Post-Strike, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Programming: General, etc, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Portugal Radio Documentaries, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: KPFA News Training, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: News Training: Background, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: San Francisco Bureau, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Labor Desk Fundraising, etc., 1976-1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: UE 14-12, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Alan Snitow Files: Letters, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: KPFA News, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Dellmas Interview, 1978 July (Box 3, Folder 15)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: News Scripts: Milk and Moscone, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Misc News Stories, circa 1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: General, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: 3-Mile Island Script and Letters, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: KPFA News, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Last Days at KPFA as News Director, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Livermore Lab Anti-Nuke Reports: Reports from Jail, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Livermore Lab Anti-Nuke Demo: Documentary and Background, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: UN Disarmament Session: Reporting, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Pacifica, 1984-1989 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Telecom Radio Project: Scripts, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Pacifica Blow-up, 1999-2002 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Basic National News, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: National News: Planning and Budgets, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: National News: Promotion, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: National News: Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: International Desk: Funding, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Energy Desk: Proposals, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: National News: Fundraising and Correspondence, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: National News: Prospectus and Drafts, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Quotes/Facts, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: News Meeting and Bureau Chief Hire, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: National News PTFP Facilities, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: NTIA Grant, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Beatch Fund, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Correspondence National Office, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: News Needs Questionnaire: NFCB on National News, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: National News Training Program, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: International News: Proposals to the Left, In These Times, Draft Letter, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Business Articles, California Public Radio, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Demo Convention, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Letter to Myself, circa 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Dem Party Convention, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Jewish Community Censorship Articles, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Democratic Socialists of America (DSA): Minorities, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: Democratic Socialists of America (DSA): Media Issue, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
- KPFA Pacifica Radio: What's Left: Script, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Alan Snitow Files: Soviet Articles: Published and Not, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Alan Snitow Files: Soviet Trip, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Alan Snitow Files: Elena Zelnitskay Interview and Article, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Alan Snitow Files: Gang of 4: Jews and Nicaragua, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Alan Snitow Files: Soviet I-V: EWS, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Alan Snitow Files: Diary: Leningrad-Moscow, 1990 March (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Alan Snitow Files: Diary: Soviet Trip (Back to Front)/Interview Notes (Front to Back), undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Alan Snitow Files: Moscow: Cassette Tape Logs, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Alan Snitow Files: Diary, 1989 October (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Alan Snitow Files: Cassette Tape Logs and Notes: Moscow, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Alan Snitow Files: Cassette Tape Logs: Moscow, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Alan Snitow Files: Soviet New Left, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Alan Snitow Files: Democratic Platform: SDA, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Alan Snitow Files: Gang of 4: Research: Israel Arms Nicaragua Dictator, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Alan Snitow Files: Santa Cruz Talks, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Alan Snitow Files: Nuclear Freeze Articles, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Alan Snitow Files: KPFA "In These Times" Clips, Bay Guardian, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Alan Snitow Files: Articles in Misc Publications, 1976-2006 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Blacks and Jews: Research Interviews, 1993 November (Box 5, Folder 16-18)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Blacks and Jews: Interview Transcripts, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Blacks and Jews: Interview Transcripts, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 21, Box 6, Folder 1)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Thirst: Interview Transcripts: Bolivia, India, Stockton, CA, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 2-4)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Secrets of Silicon Valley: Jan Krieg & SHC, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Secrets of Silicon Valley: Magda, Auram, Wiskey Gulch, Clinton, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Secrets of Silicon Valley: Transcripts: Raj Jayadev Temp Work, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Company Town: Transcripts of Interviews, 2015-2016 (Box 6, Folder 11-13)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Between Two Worlds: Transcripts, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 14-17)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Between Two Worlds: Not Used Transcripts, 2009-2010 (Box 6, Folder 18, Box 7, Folder 1)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Offshoring: Transcripts, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Blacks and Jews: Radio Series Final Transcripts, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Blacks and Jews: Film Transcript, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Secrets of Silicon Valley: Film Transcript, circa 2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Thirst: Film Transcript, circa 2004 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Offshoring: Work in Progress Transcript, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Snitow Kaufman Productions: Between Two Worlds: Film Transcript, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Drones: Final Transcripts, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Company Town: Film Transcript, circa 2015 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Blacks and Jews, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Secrets of Silicon Valley, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: POV Press: Thirst, 2004-2006 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Thirst Press, 2004-2005 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Between Two Worlds Press, 2011-2012 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Drones in My Backyard, 2013 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Snitow Kaufman Productions: Company Town, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Alan Snitow Interview for Movie KPFA on the Air, 1998 (Box 9, Cd 9)
- Between Two Worlds, 2011 (Box 9, Dvd 1)
- Blacks and Jews, 1997 (Box 9, Dvd 2)
- Drones in My Backyard, 2013 (Box 9, Dvd 3)
- Ezekiel's Wheels, 2007 (Box 9, Dvd 4)
- KPFA on the Air, 2000 (Box 9, Cd 10)
- Secrets of Silicon Valley, 2001 (Box 9, Dvd 5)
- Radio Series: Blacks and Jews (Pacifica Radio Archvies), 1997 (Box 9, Cd 11-14)
- Thirst, 2004 (Box 9, Dvd 6)
- The San Francisco Mime Troupe in 'Oil & Water': A Play in 2 Acts, 2013 (Box 9, Dvd 7)
- Water is Life: Solidrity with Standing Rock, 2017 (Box 9, Dvd 8)